ericcressey.com 2019-04-03

# » Privacy Policy

The Web site [www.ericcressey.com ](http://ericcressey.com/)(the “Site”) is provided by Cressey Training Systems, LLC.  Throughout this Privacy Policy, the words “we,” “us,” and “our” refer to Cressey Training Systems.  By accessing or using this Site, by registering as a member of this Site, or by becoming an online training customer, you consent to the use of your Personal Data (defined below) as described in this Privacy Policy (“Policy”).  If you are unwilling to consent to our collection and use of your Personal Data as described in this Policy or are unwilling to accept the terms in the Terms of Use [ **Terms of Use**](https://ericcressey.com/terms-of-use), you should not use the Site.

Collection and Use of Personal Data

Your privacy is important to us.  We at times collect, retain, and utilize Personal Data about you to operate our business and to make services and other opportunities available to you.  The term “Personal Data” means personal information that Cressey Training Systems obtains about you that can be reasonably used to identify you, including your name and email address.  We recognize and respect your privacy concerns about your Personal Data.  We obtain Personal Data in a variety of ways (for example, directly from your Site registration, from your other transactions or experiences with EricCressey.com, including comments and information that you submit when utilizing the social networking aspects of the Site (e.g., blogs) or from other third parties).

Disclosure of Information

Except as indicated within this Policy, we will not sell, rent or transfer your Personal Data to or otherwise share your Personal Data with third parties.  We may share or transfer your Personal Data as directed to do so by you.  We may use your Personal Data to notify you of EricCressey.com Site developments/features and to update you on events or projects that we are participating in or having that may interest you.

We may otherwise transfer Personal Data to third-party vendors who assist us in operating the Site.  For example, a third-party consultant might have access to your Personal Data in the course of providing database management services to us.  All or our vendors operate under applicable federal and state laws regarding consumer privacy and data security.  The Site also uses PayPal and 1ShoppingCart.com to allow for payments for products and services.  Your transaction will be governed by the privacy policies of these companies.

We may, in our sole discretion, share or transfer your Personal Data where permitted or required by law, to comply with the legal process (for example, we may disclose your information as necessary to comply with an authorized civil, criminal or regulatory investigation), to protect the security or integrity of our databases or the Site, to protect our business or reputation, to take precautions against legal liability, in the event of a business transition (see below), to protect and defend our rights or property, or for resolving disputes, inquiries or complaints with respect to your use of the Site.

Furthermore, we may also provide our partners and other third parties who might benefit from the information with aggregated data (i.e., compiled data that does not in itself identify you) for research and other purposes.

 Log Files

As is true of most Web sites, our Site gathers certain information automatically and stores it in log files.  This information, which cannot be reasonably used to identify you and does not qualify as Personal Data for purposes of this Policy, includes Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.  We may use this information to track user habits and improve the functionality of the Site as a result of our observations.

We use cookies to passively store information about your use of the Site, including your preferences and other session information.  A “cookie” is a small text file stored on your computer. You may be able to configure your browser to accept or reject all or some cookies or notify you when a cookie is set.  You may need to enable cookies, however, in order to use certain features of the Site.

 Personal Data Submitted by You within Site’s Common Areas and Blogs

If you choose, you may post comments, questions, and other information (including Personal Data, if you choose) at the Site to be reviewed by fellow users.  Information posted by you to community areas of the Site (such as blogs) is accessible by all users  We cannot control the actions of other users with whom you may choose to share your Personal Data through these features.  You also understand that such information might be re-shared or copied by other users.  Further, you understand and acknowledge that, even after removal, copies of submissions you made, including Personal Data submitted, may remain viewable in cached and archived pages or if other users have copied or stored such information.  Information shared with us through such common areas or through any other means may be reproduced by us as described in the [Terms of Use](https://ericcressey.com/terms-of-use) .

You should exercise caution in sharing your Personal Data through any of the above-described Site features.

Any improper collection or misuse of Personal Data provided on the Site is a violation of the Cresey Training Systems Terms of Use and should be reported to [ec@ericcressey.com](mailto:ec@ericcressey.com).

Links to Other Sites

You should know that while visiting the Site, you may be directed, through links, to other Web sites that are beyond our control.  We are not responsible for the privacy practices and policies of such Web sites.

 Maintenance of Accurate Information

We have established procedures to correct inaccurate information in a timely manner. If you have any reason to believe that Personal Data about you that is stored and maintained by us is incorrect, please contact us by email at [ec@ericcressey.com](mailto:ec@ericcressey.com).   ** **

Protection of Information

We strive to maintain the reliability, accuracy, completeness and currency of your Personal Data in our databases and to protect the privacy and security of our databases and the data we collect.  Any Personal Data that you provide to us will be stored on remote computer network servers.  Our service provider maintains reasonable physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect the confidentiality of your Personal Data. The security measures in place on the Site and computer systems aim to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of the information you provide to us.  If you have any questions or concerns regarding the security of your information, please email us at ec@ericcressey.com.

Business Transitions

In the event [EricCressey.com](http://ericcressey.com/) goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your Personal Data might be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via this Site of any such change in ownership or control of your Personal Data.

Changes in Our Privacy Policy

If we decide to change this Policy, we will post the changes at this Site and at other places we deem appropriate.  We reserve the right to modify this Policy at any time, so please review it frequently.

By visiting this Site and communicating electronically with us, you consent to the processing and transfer of your data as set out in this Policy.

Effective Date

This Policy is effective as of November 17, 2014.

Contact Us

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding this Policy, please contact Cressey Training Systems by e-mail: [ec@ericcressey.com](mailto:ec@ericcressey.com).
